<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-28T14:42:47-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sam Hains</title><subtitle>Sam Hains is a programmer and designer from Melbourne, Australia. He is currently completing his Masters degree at NYU's ITP program.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning" /><published>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial learning phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I do at the beginning of a learning journey, is conduct intensive initial research. In this phase I chaotically consume all information available. Whether the subject is Post-Structuralism, a video game or spiritual practice: I consult internet forums, social information platforms, knowledgeable friends and acquaintances. I take advantage of different forms of educational media including text, video, conversation and audio depending on what my daily commitments are. For example, the transit becomes an opportunity for podcasts and audiobooks. I gain an initial sense of the subject of my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting my learning journey with this process allows me to quickly ‘get up to speed’, however the uncritical nature of consuming consensus can be problematic. By absorbing the existing thought patterns on a subject, I can inadvertently internalise the prejudices of a system which might limit my imagination later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the journey is characterised by excitement and enthusiasm. I am energized by a new idea worlds and fast initial progress. I am ambitious about what this learning will bring for me and I fantasize about myself as someone skilled or knowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortality phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rate of learning begins to slow, and I have thoughts about learning something different, or returning to something I already know. I am reminded by the scale of sustained commitment  necessary to achieve fluency in a new subject. I doubt whether further information or mastery will have a greater relevance to my ‘practice’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slower pace of learning can result in distractions such as the allure of future ‘rewards’ or the glamour of being knowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was I drawn to this subject in the first place?  Was I seeking external or internal gratification? To maintain ambition I need to examine my motivations and develop a justification for continuing in this process. I am at risk of moving onto another subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding a rhythm and the maturity phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I have found the justification for continuing with this process, I am able to move to the beginnings of a more mature learning relationship. This phase is typically announced to me through the lack or need for an interactive learning community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create this sustainable learning relationship, I introduce structure and social incentive via learning communities. Shared learning experience has the ability to reinvigorate the learning process in a more sustainable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this collaborative, community driven mode of learning that I find my most sustainable and meaningful long-term projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Initial learning phase</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TAA - Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TAA - Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Teayoon Choi (mjr619@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tchoi8/teachingasart2018&quot;&gt;Class Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Teayoon Choi (mjr619@nyu.edu) Class Github</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Duchamp’s Fountain - The Last Artwork</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Duchamp's Fountain - The Last Artwork" /><published>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tragic Aesthetic - Deleuze/Nietszche Art as ‘exposing the lie’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How could we ever recover from this work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“art is the highest power of falsehood, it magnifies the “world as error”, it sanctifies the lie; the will to deception is turned into a superior ideal… The activity of life is like a power of falsehood, of duping, dissimulating, dazzling and seducing. But, in order to be brought into effect, this power of falsehood must be selected, redoubled or repeated and thus elevated to a higher power. The power of falsehood must be taken as far as a will to deceive, an artistic will which alone is capable of competing which invents the lies that raise falsehood to this highest affirmative power, that turns the will to deceive into something which is affirmed in the power of falsehood. For the artist, appearance no longer means negation of the real in this world but this kind of selection, correction, redoubling and affirmation. Then the truth perhaps take on a new sense. Truth is appearance. Truth means bringing of power into effect, raising to the highest power. In Nietzsche, “we the artists” = “we the seekers after knowledge or truth” = “we the inventors of new possibilities of life”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new discourse was founded on the necessity of finding a way of defining art which would permit the readymades to live comfortably side by side with Rembrandt’s portraits and Constable’s landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;identified by the complacency and smugness they brought to their understanding of art, in particular of the ‘old masters’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;author and art critic Calvin Tomkins declared that Duchamp had “quietly undermined several centuries of Western art with his readymades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigel Warburton puts it, “The idea that all works of art must be the product of the artist’s hand, or that they must be aesthetically beautiful or emotionally profound, is hard to sustain once works like Fountain have been accepted into the mainstream” (The Art Question, 2003). In that case, what made it an art object must be, as Tomkins had it, because “the artist was merely someone who signed things.” Hence whatever the artist signed, or submitted for exhibition, was ipso facto art. In short, the philosophy of art now proclaimed an astonishing doctrine: no qualities or attributes of the object need be consulted, nor were there any criteria for evaluating things designated as art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the meaning and purpose of this distinction between art and ‘real world objects’. This distinction seems to collapse as soon as an interrogation begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of creating these barriers to the gallery? Can a brillo box or a urinal be let into an art gallery? Who seeks to benefit from preventing this. The masters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to suggest we need to uncritically accept the Brillo Box as art, rather we should be looking for transformative experiences and the question ‘is it art?’ banal and irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Tragic Aesthetic - Deleuze/Nietszche Art as ‘exposing the lie’ How could we ever recover from this work?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1f8BIO_TbruTUevjWLsD9oPRnsYxjgPye&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com) Google Drive</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cuFUq-Xiu4FK_FoxgHGfH6loz6GWUHg8v6uiBNkOGLw/edit#&quot;&gt;Class Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu) Class Syllabus</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itp.nyu.edu/classes/lipp/&quot;&gt;Class Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu) Class Page</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Algorithmic Composition Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/algo-comp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algorithmic Composition Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/algo-comp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/algo-comp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: R Luke DuBois (dubois@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IDMNYU/ITPG-GT-2524-SP18-DuBois/wiki&quot;&gt;Class Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: R Luke DuBois (dubois@nyu.edu) Class Wiki</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2 Materials for Fab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Materials for Fab" /><published>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html">&lt;p&gt;For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translucent paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto blade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got the materials.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila!
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object. PARTS AND TOOLS Foam Translucent paper Drill press Glue Stick Exacto blade PROCESS Got the materials. Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles. Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size. Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam. Voila!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mounting Motors Assignment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mounting Motors Assignment" /><published>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban saw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sizes of wooden Dowels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then drilled the screws into the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is is. Ugly, but functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246881087&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">PARTS AND TOOLS Drill Press Foam Drill Exacto knife Ban saw 2 sizes of wooden Dowels I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it. I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw. I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole. I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags. I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of. I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount. I then drilled the screws into the servo mount. I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely. I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo! All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires. I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden. Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism. I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel. Worked well! It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags. My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides. Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7. I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag. I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it. Here is is. Ugly, but functioning. CONCLUSION I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html">&lt;p&gt;This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246076170&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246517068&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’. The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds. Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.</summary></entry></feed>