<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-31T19:21:44-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sam Hains</title><subtitle>Sam Hains is a programmer and designer from Melbourne, Australia. He is currently completing his Masters degree at NYU's ITP program.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">High School Curriculum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/31/high-school-curriculum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High School Curriculum" /><published>2018-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/31/high-school-curriculum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/31/high-school-curriculum.html">&lt;p&gt;This curriculum is designed to… (eg.) empower students for independence, while protecting them from certain common problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Background **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction of community through social experience
Multi layered participatory structures
Role of social media&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual world building, collaborative building in virtual worlds
Simulated financial education
Philosophy and critical theory
Media art and history
Performance art
Queer theory gender …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning objective: Students will learn “” in a collection of classes, over a semester, an academic year or degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning outcome: Student will achieve “ “ through the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teaching-philosophy&quot;&gt;Teaching philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Age appropriate. Harmonious society, learn to live together. Egalatarian, less emphasis on  competition. Not just academic, but also experiential. Deep interest and curiosity about the world - how to inspire this? About inspiration, questions. Community - how to develop? Cooking, Gardening skills. Movement and dance. When is the child ready? What does the child need? Integration of thinking, doing and making. Movement instead of sports. Biology bones, physics gravity -&amp;gt; gymnastics and summersault. Music and Dance integral to the development of thinking capacity. Musicology and ethnography. All teachers to strive towards wholeness in lesson. Enjoyment of working. Confidence building, before other things.   Used to independent working. Non-judgemental, creativity, respectful of other people. Competition not with other people, but with selves. Thinking of the teachers is very important. Freedom with students. Teaching is a learning profession - Not there to deliver knowledge but you are there to grow with children.  About wanting to learn, wanting to learn and wanting to meet the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A curriculum which acknowledges the social responsibilities of education must present situations where problems are relevant to the problems of living together, and where observation and information are calculated to develop social insight and interest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework Notes:
 Longterm outcomes. not specific classes but the way they connect. what are the goals, why will this work? why wont it? less interested in educational structure.  how could you help yourself go to college they want, but circumvent that and find alternatives..Programming as virtual possibility and social currency. scripting in second life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One big problem for me was that because I was good at maths so I felt like i was typified as this kind of student. I got categorized as a ‘maths student’ and it seemed like I shouldn’t pursue arts or creativity. I spent a long time unlearning this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;friends that were very engaged in learning about art and literature. we would meet and talk about these things. it was motivating. Then i think i took this approach of ‘nerding out’ online, and found online communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove religion - replace with philosophy and spirituality
 Remove sport - make non-competitive&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This curriculum is designed to… (eg.) empower students for independence, while protecting them from certain common problems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Internet self: ideation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/30/internet-self-ideation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Internet self: ideation" /><published>2018-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/30/internet-self-ideation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/30/internet-self-ideation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the end of a panel at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, where his comments were webcast, he was asked for his prediction on the future of the web. “I will answer very simply that the Internet will disappear,” Eric Schmidt said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in exploring some of the implications of this dystopian idea shared by Google CEO, Eric Schmidt, that the internet is ‘disappearing’ into something indistinguishable from our everyday reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, ideas pertaining to our online personas, archives of personal data (we no longer own), cyber-bullying and contemporary notions of the ‘self’. What happens when our digital ‘stories’ begin to take on lives of their own? What if media companies, or other nefarious actors found ways to decontextualize and appropriate you to algorithmically generate scandalous, clickbait stories?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyper-localised gossip generating networks riff on your intimate personal data. Machinic auteurs remix your irony and sarcasm. You are transformed into a global meme sensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive installation proposal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘user’ participates in a simulated space, a mixed reality. The space contains objects that are being projected onto and can be interacted with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some (non-mutually exclusive) ideas for the objects in this space involve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A collection of mannequin faces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A surreal collection of readymades - disembodied mannequin parts, chairs and cages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A chair, a desk and a couple of monitors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blondesongstress.files.wordpress.com/2014/02/andrc3a9-masson-surrealist-mannequin-head-in-a-cage-19381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mannequin by André Masson, Denise Bellon, 1938&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system surveils the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user is asked to participate in a series of ‘Are you a human?’ tests like those seen as security checks in modern web browsers. These tests will be more invasive and comprehensive than usual asking for vocal feedback and facial expressions. I hope this process encourages the user to reflect on the ways in which we have normalized these frequent ‘humanity tests’ that computers give us. In the wild, these tests are more about having an individual participate in training an ‘AI system’ than testing if the user is a human. I hope to play with this idea - ‘the machine’ has already began testing us, questioning us - how else is it exploiting our naivety?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.access-ai.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/1417716998-google-says-rip-captcha-sort-of-610x500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user will be asked to speak to the system, through a mask that might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/61dwPV5niOL._SY355_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The face and voice data captured from the tests are projected onto mannequin faces. The users face and voice have been stolen and are now being contorted.  They watch themselves in a performance that they did not authorize. They watch themselves behave like a ‘buffoon’ to an applauding, simulated audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience members applaud with the mindless cruelty of a nightmare. Their contorted smiles are stolen from other visitors who have come before them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-l1EbxZNBfU/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jean-Paul Gaultier Exhibit at N.G.V, 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Additional Ideas **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There might be an interface that provides an archive of previous visitors to the space, and the participant may have the option to further remix or reorganize that persons virtual identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/index.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;INDEX by Łukasz Furma, 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/lEtiuVVuWL8/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Uknown source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system might function as a database of ‘shadow participants’ who can be called forth to enact their artificial performance at any moment to an applauding virtual audience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At the end of a panel at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, where his comments were webcast, he was asked for his prediction on the future of the web. “I will answer very simply that the Internet will disappear,” Eric Schmidt said.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning" /><published>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/28/learning.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial learning phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I do at the beginning of a learning journey, is conduct intensive initial research. In this phase I chaotically consume all information available. Whether the subject is Post-Structuralism, a video game or spiritual practice: I consult internet forums, social information platforms, knowledgeable friends and acquaintances. I take advantage of different forms of educational media including text, video, conversation and audio depending on what my daily commitments are. For example, the transit becomes an opportunity for podcasts and audiobooks. I gain an initial sense of the subject of my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting my learning journey with this process allows me to quickly ‘get up to speed’, however the uncritical nature of consuming consensus can be problematic. By absorbing the existing thought patterns on a subject, I can inadvertently internalise the prejudices of a system which might limit my imagination later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the journey is characterised by excitement and enthusiasm. I am energized by a new idea worlds and fast initial progress. I am ambitious about what this learning will bring for me and I fantasize about myself as someone skilled or knowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortality phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rate of learning begins to slow, and I have thoughts about learning something different, or returning to something I already know. I am reminded by the scale of sustained commitment  necessary to achieve fluency in a new subject. I doubt whether further information or mastery will have a greater relevance to my ‘practice’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slower pace of learning can result in distractions such as the allure of future ‘rewards’ or the glamour of being knowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was I drawn to this subject in the first place?  Was I seeking external or internal gratification? To maintain ambition I need to examine my motivations and develop a justification for continuing in this process. I am at risk of moving onto another subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding a rhythm and the maturity phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I have found the justification for continuing with this process, I am able to move to the beginnings of a more mature learning relationship. This phase is typically announced to me through the lack or need for an interactive learning community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create this sustainable learning relationship, I introduce structure and social incentive via learning communities. Shared learning experience has the ability to reinvigorate the learning process in a more sustainable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this collaborative, community driven mode of learning that I find my most sustainable and meaningful long-term projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Initial learning phase</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Video Footage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/video-footage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Video Footage" /><published>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/video-footage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/video-footage.html">&lt;p&gt;To begin with, I experimented with using the zoom to find landscapes within landscapes. By focusing on things up-close, I was able to play with scale. As I experimented with the digital zoom, I discovered that it introduces some interesting distortions and artefacts into the images. I introduced a constraint: shoot all of the video footage with the phone’s digital zoom ‘maxed-out’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some interesting consequences of this. It created a discrepancy between the way my eye saw the world and the way the world looked on my phone - which created some surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consequence was the way that the zoom made my breathing and movement more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the way that screens and lights looked when zoomed all the way in. The combination of digital zoom, and the rapid movement of screen lights created some interesting distortions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my journey progressed, I found myself drawn to the way that electronics and screens appeared as integrated into the urban environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, looking over the footage - I’m not crazy about it. I’m not sure I have an eye for photography. I think I might have better luck curating stuff from my virtual lives…  :S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what my folder looks like:
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/sprite_gen/5.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some sample footage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/253187276&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/253187337&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To begin with, I experimented with using the zoom to find landscapes within landscapes. By focusing on things up-close, I was able to play with scale. As I experimented with the digital zoom, I discovered that it introduces some interesting distortions and artefacts into the images. I introduced a constraint: shoot all of the video footage with the phone’s digital zoom ‘maxed-out’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sprite Generator</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/sprite-generator.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sprite Generator" /><published>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/sprite-generator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/28/sprite-generator.html">&lt;p&gt;As a side project for this week, I decided to build a sprite generator. The goal was to build a system which could take/scrape sprite sheets (see below) from websites such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://spritedatabase.net/&quot;&gt;spritedatabase.net&lt;/a&gt; and procedurally animate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/sprite_gen/1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to create generative pixel art scenes that could be used in a performance context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some vague ideas about where this could be used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performance where I am performing endless, absurd labour tending to a virtual farm, fishtank etc. while my life falls apart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A parody and pastiche of Video-game streaming culture where I walk an audience through a game where the only mechanic is death and complexity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More abstract video performances that combine aesthetics from virtual worlds and pixel art. Base materials might be built from ‘field recordings in virtual space’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An twisted, futuristic arcade generator game, where the game is purely about generation of complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built a python script that uses computer vision technology to locate the sprites in the sheet, then procedurally cut them up and turn them into image sequence animations. The code for this can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samhains/sprite-generator&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works pretty well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built a basic environment in Touch Designer to procedurally place and scatter the sprites. Some screenshots and footage from this system are seen here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/253171702&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/sprite_gen/3.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/253171775&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/sprite_gen/2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very ‘uncurated’, first play with these new tools. I like the chaos, and colours and complexity of the aesthetic - but it is just a start. Some things I want to try next are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add performance controls to enlarge sprite and move sprite and generate new screen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give sprites a random walk to enhance the ‘feedback trails effect’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playing with different backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working with more curated and conceptual datasets of sprites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incorporate footage from other virtual environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add probability of different sprite enclosures - sprites in jail? sprites at work? etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As a side project for this week, I decided to build a sprite generator. The goal was to build a system which could take/scrape sprite sheets (see below) from websites such as spritedatabase.net and procedurally animate them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TAA - Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TAA - Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/taa/2018/01/27/taa-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Teayoon Choi (mjr619@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tchoi8/teachingasart2018&quot;&gt;Class Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Teayoon Choi (mjr619@nyu.edu) Class Github</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Fountain - Art as Subversion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Fountain - Art as Subversion" /><published>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tate.org.uk/art/images/work/T/T07/T07573_10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duchamp’s revolutionary artwork ‘The Fountain’ is art as subversion of the familiar -  sanctifying the lie of art as some kind of ‘superior ideal’. Duchamp exposed complacency and smugness surrounding our notions of art, initiating the motion to collapse the deception at the core of our distinction between ‘art’ and the ‘real world’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new discourse was born out of the ‘readymade’: What kind of definition of ‘art’ could encompass both a Urinal purchased from a factory and a Pablo Picasso painting? Was such a definition necessary? Previous definitions of art involved requirements such technical benchmarks, notions of beauty or measures of emotional profundity which became difficult to sustain once works like ‘The Fountain’ were acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is art in a culture that no longer has any objective standards around its ideal form or content?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My understanding is that our attempts to create definitions for an objective ‘art’ (or anything) are in vein. For Deleuze, the role of art is to magnify this sense of the intuitive, singular ‘world as error’, and to ‘sanctify the lie’ by elevating our self-deceptions about ‘objective reality’ to a thing of mysterious beauty (‘Nietzsche and Philosophy’, Gilles Deleuze 1962). Art has the capacity to excite our perceptual apparatus, and change the way that we interpret the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discourse which emerged from the ‘readymade’ revolving around developing a classification system for what is and isn’t art - is not important. For art is inherently a project to subvert the familiar. If the familiar or ‘clearly knowable’ has become our conception of art itself, Art will be the force that deconstructs that notion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/studio/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cuFUq-Xiu4FK_FoxgHGfH6loz6GWUHg8v6uiBNkOGLw/edit#&quot;&gt;Class Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu) Class Syllabus</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1f8BIO_TbruTUevjWLsD9oPRnsYxjgPye&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com) Google Drive</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itp.nyu.edu/classes/lipp/&quot;&gt;Class Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu) Class Page</summary></entry></feed>