<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-24T11:18:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sam Hains</title><subtitle>Sam Hains is a programmer and designer from Melbourne, Australia. He is currently completing his Masters degree at NYU's ITP program.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Duchamp’s Fountain - The Last Artwork</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Duchamp's Fountain - The Last Artwork" /><published>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/24/duchamp-fountain-the-last-artwork.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tragic Aesthetic - Deleuze/Nietszche Art as ‘exposing the lie’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How could we ever recover from this work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“art is the highest power of falsehood, it magnifies the “world as error”, it sanctifies the lie; the will to deception is turned into a superior ideal… The activity of life is like a power of falsehood, of duping, dissimulating, dazzling and seducing. But, in order to be brought into effect, this power of falsehood must be selected, redoubled or repeated and thus elevated to a higher power. The power of falsehood must be taken as far as a will to deceive, an artistic will which alone is capable of competing which invents the lies that raise falsehood to this highest affirmative power, that turns the will to deceive into something which is affirmed in the power of falsehood. For the artist, appearance no longer means negation of the real in this world but this kind of selection, correction, redoubling and affirmation. Then the truth perhaps take on a new sense. Truth is appearance. Truth means bringing of power into effect, raising to the highest power. In Nietzsche, “we the artists” = “we the seekers after knowledge or truth” = “we the inventors of new possibilities of life”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new discourse was founded on the necessity of finding a way of defining art which would permit the readymades to live comfortably side by side with Rembrandt’s portraits and Constable’s landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;identified by the complacency and smugness they brought to their understanding of art, in particular of the ‘old masters’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;author and art critic Calvin Tomkins declared that Duchamp had “quietly undermined several centuries of Western art with his readymades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigel Warburton puts it, “The idea that all works of art must be the product of the artist’s hand, or that they must be aesthetically beautiful or emotionally profound, is hard to sustain once works like Fountain have been accepted into the mainstream” (The Art Question, 2003). In that case, what made it an art object must be, as Tomkins had it, because “the artist was merely someone who signed things.” Hence whatever the artist signed, or submitted for exhibition, was ipso facto art. In short, the philosophy of art now proclaimed an astonishing doctrine: no qualities or attributes of the object need be consulted, nor were there any criteria for evaluating things designated as art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the meaning and purpose of this distinction between art and ‘real world objects’. This distinction seems to collapse as soon as an interrogation begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of creating these barriers to the gallery? Can a brillo box or a urinal be let into an art gallery? Who seeks to benefit from preventing this. The masters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to suggest we need to uncritically accept the Brillo Box as art, rather we should be looking for transformative experiences and the question ‘is it art?’ banal and irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Tragic Aesthetic - Deleuze/Nietszche Art as ‘exposing the lie’ How could we ever recover from this work?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/rcia/2018/01/23/rcia-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1f8BIO_TbruTUevjWLsD9oPRnsYxjgPye&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Georgia Krantz (georgiakrantz@gmail.com) Google Drive</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-dev/2018/01/23/project-dev-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cuFUq-Xiu4FK_FoxgHGfH6loz6GWUHg8v6uiBNkOGLw/edit#&quot;&gt;Class Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Danny Rozin (danny.rozin@nyu.edu) Class Syllabus</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Class Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Class Resources" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lipp/2018/01/23/lipp-resources.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itp.nyu.edu/classes/lipp/&quot;&gt;Class Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructor Details: Matt Romein (mjr619@nyu.edu) Class Page</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2 Materials for Fab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Materials for Fab" /><published>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html">&lt;p&gt;For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translucent paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto blade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got the materials.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila!
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object. PARTS AND TOOLS Foam Translucent paper Drill press Glue Stick Exacto blade PROCESS Got the materials. Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles. Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size. Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam. Voila!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mounting Motors Assignment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mounting Motors Assignment" /><published>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban saw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sizes of wooden Dowels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then drilled the screws into the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is is. Ugly, but functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246881087&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">PARTS AND TOOLS Drill Press Foam Drill Exacto knife Ban saw 2 sizes of wooden Dowels I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it. I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw. I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole. I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags. I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of. I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount. I then drilled the screws into the servo mount. I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely. I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo! All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires. I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden. Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism. I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel. Worked well! It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags. My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides. Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7. I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag. I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it. Here is is. Ugly, but functioning. CONCLUSION I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html">&lt;p&gt;This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246076170&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246517068&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’. The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds. Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pcomm Final Project Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pcomm Final Project Update" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time over the last couple of weeks trying to refine some implementations of my ideas for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to modify an old fashioned telephone, that will operate as the main source of interaction for the participant. The fabrication component of this is documented &lt;a href=&quot;http://samhains.com/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some trial and error, I managed to get the telephone speaking with my audio interface by cracking open a microphone and appropriating the dynamic microphone inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of spending a (vague) estimate of 1/2 to a day  wiring the telephone ‘bells’ to the Arduino, I have stashed a couple of speakers inside the Telephone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in the process of wiring up the Telephone receiver switch to the Arduino’s digital input. This switch will keep track of where the phone receiver is. I will need to figure out a way to wire up the pull-down resistor without the space for a full breadboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also working on setting up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinkersphere.com/sensors/1256-fsr-force-sensor-pressure-sensor-arduino-compatible.html&quot;&gt;force sensor&lt;/a&gt; to communicate via the XBee microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was assisted with the help of Tom Igoes’ ‘Making Things Talk’ book  (both PHP and Node.js versions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as I am using Touch Designer as the brains of my operation, I have needed to re-write the parsing code in python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have posted the code &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/samhains/a149b8011280cb4f4e6b6451cd070d97&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to be only partially-working at this stage -  every 2nd or 3rd value responds to force. The values are not expressing ‘range’ properly either, it seems they are almost ‘on and off’ at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spent time developing the audio-reactive visuals for the installation.  When the participant talks into the headset, they will hear a looping soundscape of their own voice in  the receiver. A combination of the raw voice sound, and the soundscape are analysed to influence the visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a preview of where the visuals are at. I’m not quite happy with them yet. The first part, before it gets too trippy is a representation of the user approaching the installation. The second part is demonstrating what happens visually when they sit down, and answer the telephone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/244959856&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard to see from the video  (Couldn’t figure out how to screencap with audio) but it has been really challenging to get some ‘satisfying’ audio-visual effects.  I’m still feeling like my method of audio analysis is a little clumsy and could use refinement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an earlier video of some testing done projecting onto the screens. In this video there are no custom projection screens being fitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/243369842&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is more to do. I feel confident I can finish the basic physical components before user testing. However, I’d love to introduce some ‘kinetic sculpture’ to the ‘pile of junk’ that would respond to the voice. I feel this might bring it to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to add some sensor interaction that ‘lures’ the user in, I am thinking of using some depth sensors with some additional lights placed on the ‘junk pile’ and perhaps on the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to keep pushing the interaction and the aesthetic to create something more entertaining and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I spent a lot of time over the last couple of weeks trying to refine some implementations of my ideas for this project. I started to modify an old fashioned telephone, that will operate as the main source of interaction for the participant. The fabrication component of this is documented here. After some trial and error, I managed to get the telephone speaking with my audio interface by cracking open a microphone and appropriating the dynamic microphone inside. Instead of spending a (vague) estimate of 1/2 to a day wiring the telephone ‘bells’ to the Arduino, I have stashed a couple of speakers inside the Telephone. I am in the process of wiring up the Telephone receiver switch to the Arduino’s digital input. This switch will keep track of where the phone receiver is. I will need to figure out a way to wire up the pull-down resistor without the space for a full breadboard. I am also working on setting up a force sensor to communicate via the XBee microcontroller. This was assisted with the help of Tom Igoes’ ‘Making Things Talk’ book (both PHP and Node.js versions). However, as I am using Touch Designer as the brains of my operation, I have needed to re-write the parsing code in python. I have posted the code here. It seems to be only partially-working at this stage - every 2nd or 3rd value responds to force. The values are not expressing ‘range’ properly either, it seems they are almost ‘on and off’ at this stage. I also spent time developing the audio-reactive visuals for the installation. When the participant talks into the headset, they will hear a looping soundscape of their own voice in the receiver. A combination of the raw voice sound, and the soundscape are analysed to influence the visuals. This is a preview of where the visuals are at. I’m not quite happy with them yet. The first part, before it gets too trippy is a representation of the user approaching the installation. The second part is demonstrating what happens visually when they sit down, and answer the telephone. Hard to see from the video (Couldn’t figure out how to screencap with audio) but it has been really challenging to get some ‘satisfying’ audio-visual effects. I’m still feeling like my method of audio analysis is a little clumsy and could use refinement. Here is an earlier video of some testing done projecting onto the screens. In this video there are no custom projection screens being fitted. CONCLUSION There is more to do. I feel confident I can finish the basic physical components before user testing. However, I’d love to introduce some ‘kinetic sculpture’ to the ‘pile of junk’ that would respond to the voice. I feel this might bring it to life. I also need to add some sensor interaction that ‘lures’ the user in, I am thinking of using some depth sensors with some additional lights placed on the ‘junk pile’ and perhaps on the chair. I still need to keep pushing the interaction and the aesthetic to create something more entertaining and interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Telephone Enclosure</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Telephone Enclosure" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html">&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;a href=&quot;http://samhains.com/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html&quot;&gt;Physical Computing final&lt;/a&gt;, I needed to hack an old telephone that will be used to interact with a pile of electronic junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This telephone needs to plug into my audio interface, as well as house an Arduino to broadcast information about where the receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dremmel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microphone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old Telephone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helping hands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I opened up the telephone to find that I would need to create some space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take the bottom of the telephone with a drill press to remove the old metal ‘plug/screws’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of trial and error with the drill bit, I found one that worked. I used a clamp to secure the telephone, and prepared the drill press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was obvious when the drill released the ‘plug/screw’ - It works great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I removed the heart of the phone, which created the perfect amount of space for my Arduino and speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to modify the receiver so that it could communicate with my audio interface. I removed the existing microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cracked open a dynamic microphone, and removed the microphone part. This piece was too large to fit inside my telephone receiver, so I needed to use the Dremmel to cut it down to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Apologies for the lack of photos, I forgot to document this process)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soldered the new Microphone to the telephone receiver, and connected this to the Arduino enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am considering wiring up the Arduino directly to the ‘bells’ instead of faking the ‘ring’ with speakers, however I’m not sure this is the best use of a half-day/days work. The case seems to create a nice amount of resonance, even without ‘speaker holes’.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my Physical Computing final, I needed to hack an old telephone that will be used to interact with a pile of electronic junk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Concept Development ‘Talking to Machines’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Concept Development 'Talking to Machines'" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html">&lt;p&gt;This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time sketching. And eventually I arrived at this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the impracticality, implausibility and difficulty of the ‘interactive room’ aspect of the project, I have scaled down the project and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it became clear that to power 5+ monitors on my laptop, I would need expensive adapters or a secondary computer or GPU. This started to sound like more hassle than it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, The room of monitors has been replaced with an obelisk of found-electronics. This may involve anything from televisions, microwaves, Furby’s and minibar fridges. All of these items will have projection screens retrofitted to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interaction has also been overhauled. Rather than using depth sensors and movement the main interaction now is done through the phone in a sedentary position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the participant sits down, a phone on their right will start ringing. They will answer the phone to find that their voice creates  a swelling feedback loop that influences and effects the images that they see in the frightening obelisk in front of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obelisk is a monsterous internet of things, and is still intended to be scary or unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that this new direction makes the act of ‘communicating with the machine’ more direct while there being much to explore in terms of fleshing out a satisfying voice-reactive experience through the telephone and video sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have begun  modifying the telephone so that it can react interactively, and interface with my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The microphone is being replaced with microphone that will provide a separate pre-amplified signal to my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also begun laser cutting scrap materials to start getting the ‘retrofit screens’ ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to wiring up the telephone, the ringer and the screens all together, and getting into fleshing out and designing the audio-visual interaction.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’. I spent a lot of time sketching. And eventually I arrived at this: Due to the impracticality, implausibility and difficulty of the ‘interactive room’ aspect of the project, I have scaled down the project and interaction. Furthermore, it became clear that to power 5+ monitors on my laptop, I would need expensive adapters or a secondary computer or GPU. This started to sound like more hassle than it was worth. As a result, The room of monitors has been replaced with an obelisk of found-electronics. This may involve anything from televisions, microwaves, Furby’s and minibar fridges. All of these items will have projection screens retrofitted to them. The interaction has also been overhauled. Rather than using depth sensors and movement the main interaction now is done through the phone in a sedentary position. When the participant sits down, a phone on their right will start ringing. They will answer the phone to find that their voice creates a swelling feedback loop that influences and effects the images that they see in the frightening obelisk in front of them. The obelisk is a monsterous internet of things, and is still intended to be scary or unsettling. I believe that this new direction makes the act of ‘communicating with the machine’ more direct while there being much to explore in terms of fleshing out a satisfying voice-reactive experience through the telephone and video sculpture. I have begun modifying the telephone so that it can react interactively, and interface with my audio interface. The microphone is being replaced with microphone that will provide a separate pre-amplified signal to my audio interface. I have also begun laser cutting scrap materials to start getting the ‘retrofit screens’ ready. CONCLUSION Looking forward to wiring up the telephone, the ringer and the screens all together, and getting into fleshing out and designing the audio-visual interaction.</summary></entry></feed>