<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-09T23:44:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sam Hains</title><subtitle>Sam Hains is a programmer and designer from Melbourne, Australia. He is currently completing his Masters degree at NYU's ITP program.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">2 Materials for Fab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Materials for Fab" /><published>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/15/2-materials.html">&lt;p&gt;For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translucent paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto blade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got the materials.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila!
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_2_materials/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my 2 materials assignment I decided to play with foam, and translucent paper to create a rear projection object. PARTS AND TOOLS Foam Translucent paper Drill press Glue Stick Exacto blade PROCESS Got the materials. Used a drill press with a large circular drill bit to create circles. Used an Exacto blade to cut the translucent paper to size. Used a glue stick to stick the transparent paper to the foam. Voila!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mounting Motors Assignment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mounting Motors Assignment" /><published>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/12/11/mounting-motors-assignment.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exacto knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban saw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sizes of wooden Dowels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then drilled the screws into the servo mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_motor_mount/18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is is. Ugly, but functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246881087&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">PARTS AND TOOLS Drill Press Foam Drill Exacto knife Ban saw 2 sizes of wooden Dowels I really like the colour of this foam material I’ve been seeing around the shop. When I encountered some in the junk pile, I was happy to take it. I cut down the foam to a workable size using the Ban saw. I then cut up some Dowels that would be used as the flag pole. I found some used arcade tickets from the Junk shelf that I sticky-taped to the Dowels to create flags. I found some cardboard tube ends that I decided to build a ‘pulley’ system out of. I glued this first to help keep it in pace while drilling holes for the servo mount. I then drilled the screws into the servo mount. I used scissors to cut down the edges of the mount so that the servo could spin freely. I found that the existing hole in the foam, was already a perfect size for the servo! All that was needed was to use an ‘Exacto blade’ to cut some room for the wires. I hot-glued some foam legs on the foam board so that the motor mechanism could sit underneath and be hidden. Experimenting with some string to have the motor drive the flags revealed that a dowel would be necessary for added torque to the mechanism. I set up a drill press so that I could drill a straight hole the size of the smaller dowel. Worked well! It was more difficult than expected to set up a nicely flowing pulley/dowel set up that would rotate the flags. My strategy was to tie a small not around the dowel end, and use hot glue to secure it. I would then tie a loose knot around the pulley and roll the dowel around to get a feel for how much give would be necessary on both sides. Due to time constraints, I re-scoped the assignment, and decided to drive a single flag with the motor, rather than 7. I cut down the board to a smaller size.. and drilled a hole for the dowel flag. I spent some time getting the mechanism smooth with trial and error before making a knot and gluing it. Here is is. Ugly, but functioning. CONCLUSION I was too hasty with the Ban Saw, and cut up my material without thinking about centring the single flag that I had. I also would have liked to have done this with multiple flags. I learnt about mechanisms as well as gained added experience with general shop tools.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talking To Machine Winter Show Submission" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/12/06/taking-to-the-machine-winter-show-submission.html">&lt;p&gt;This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246076170&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/246517068&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This project is interactive visual sculpture. The project explores ideas and tropes surrounding human-machine communication through an interactive, fictional call center. The call center connects the participant to an accelerated diagram of our existing reality, loosely based on Nick Land’s science fiction poem ‘Meltdown’. The visuals contain a representation of a potential future where people have retreated from complexity into performance, role playing, virtual worlds. Here is a demo of some of the audio-visuals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pcomm Final Project Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pcomm Final Project Update" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/29/final-project-update.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time over the last couple of weeks trying to refine some implementations of my ideas for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to modify an old fashioned telephone, that will operate as the main source of interaction for the participant. The fabrication component of this is documented &lt;a href=&quot;http://samhains.com/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some trial and error, I managed to get the telephone speaking with my audio interface by cracking open a microphone and appropriating the dynamic microphone inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of spending a (vague) estimate of 1/2 to a day  wiring the telephone ‘bells’ to the Arduino, I have stashed a couple of speakers inside the Telephone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in the process of wiring up the Telephone receiver switch to the Arduino’s digital input. This switch will keep track of where the phone receiver is. I will need to figure out a way to wire up the pull-down resistor without the space for a full breadboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also working on setting up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinkersphere.com/sensors/1256-fsr-force-sensor-pressure-sensor-arduino-compatible.html&quot;&gt;force sensor&lt;/a&gt; to communicate via the XBee microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was assisted with the help of Tom Igoes’ ‘Making Things Talk’ book  (both PHP and Node.js versions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_update/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as I am using Touch Designer as the brains of my operation, I have needed to re-write the parsing code in python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have posted the code &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/samhains/a149b8011280cb4f4e6b6451cd070d97&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to be only partially-working at this stage -  every 2nd or 3rd value responds to force. The values are not expressing ‘range’ properly either, it seems they are almost ‘on and off’ at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spent time developing the audio-reactive visuals for the installation.  When the participant talks into the headset, they will hear a looping soundscape of their own voice in  the receiver. A combination of the raw voice sound, and the soundscape are analysed to influence the visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a preview of where the visuals are at. I’m not quite happy with them yet. The first part, before it gets too trippy is a representation of the user approaching the installation. The second part is demonstrating what happens visually when they sit down, and answer the telephone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/244959856&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard to see from the video  (Couldn’t figure out how to screencap with audio) but it has been really challenging to get some ‘satisfying’ audio-visual effects.  I’m still feeling like my method of audio analysis is a little clumsy and could use refinement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an earlier video of some testing done projecting onto the screens. In this video there are no custom projection screens being fitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/243369842&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is more to do. I feel confident I can finish the basic physical components before user testing. However, I’d love to introduce some ‘kinetic sculpture’ to the ‘pile of junk’ that would respond to the voice. I feel this might bring it to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to add some sensor interaction that ‘lures’ the user in, I am thinking of using some depth sensors with some additional lights placed on the ‘junk pile’ and perhaps on the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to keep pushing the interaction and the aesthetic to create something more entertaining and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I spent a lot of time over the last couple of weeks trying to refine some implementations of my ideas for this project. I started to modify an old fashioned telephone, that will operate as the main source of interaction for the participant. The fabrication component of this is documented here. After some trial and error, I managed to get the telephone speaking with my audio interface by cracking open a microphone and appropriating the dynamic microphone inside. Instead of spending a (vague) estimate of 1/2 to a day wiring the telephone ‘bells’ to the Arduino, I have stashed a couple of speakers inside the Telephone. I am in the process of wiring up the Telephone receiver switch to the Arduino’s digital input. This switch will keep track of where the phone receiver is. I will need to figure out a way to wire up the pull-down resistor without the space for a full breadboard. I am also working on setting up a force sensor to communicate via the XBee microcontroller. This was assisted with the help of Tom Igoes’ ‘Making Things Talk’ book (both PHP and Node.js versions). However, as I am using Touch Designer as the brains of my operation, I have needed to re-write the parsing code in python. I have posted the code here. It seems to be only partially-working at this stage - every 2nd or 3rd value responds to force. The values are not expressing ‘range’ properly either, it seems they are almost ‘on and off’ at this stage. I also spent time developing the audio-reactive visuals for the installation. When the participant talks into the headset, they will hear a looping soundscape of their own voice in the receiver. A combination of the raw voice sound, and the soundscape are analysed to influence the visuals. This is a preview of where the visuals are at. I’m not quite happy with them yet. The first part, before it gets too trippy is a representation of the user approaching the installation. The second part is demonstrating what happens visually when they sit down, and answer the telephone. Hard to see from the video (Couldn’t figure out how to screencap with audio) but it has been really challenging to get some ‘satisfying’ audio-visual effects. I’m still feeling like my method of audio analysis is a little clumsy and could use refinement. Here is an earlier video of some testing done projecting onto the screens. In this video there are no custom projection screens being fitted. CONCLUSION There is more to do. I feel confident I can finish the basic physical components before user testing. However, I’d love to introduce some ‘kinetic sculpture’ to the ‘pile of junk’ that would respond to the voice. I feel this might bring it to life. I also need to add some sensor interaction that ‘lures’ the user in, I am thinking of using some depth sensors with some additional lights placed on the ‘junk pile’ and perhaps on the chair. I still need to keep pushing the interaction and the aesthetic to create something more entertaining and interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Telephone Enclosure</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Telephone Enclosure" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/29/telephone-enclosure.html">&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;a href=&quot;http://samhains.com/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html&quot;&gt;Physical Computing final&lt;/a&gt;, I needed to hack an old telephone that will be used to interact with a pile of electronic junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This telephone needs to plug into my audio interface, as well as house an Arduino to broadcast information about where the receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dremmel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microphone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old Telephone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helping hands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drill Press&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I opened up the telephone to find that I would need to create some space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take the bottom of the telephone with a drill press to remove the old metal ‘plug/screws’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of trial and error with the drill bit, I found one that worked. I used a clamp to secure the telephone, and prepared the drill press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was obvious when the drill released the ‘plug/screw’ - It works great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I removed the heart of the phone, which created the perfect amount of space for my Arduino and speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to modify the receiver so that it could communicate with my audio interface. I removed the existing microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cracked open a dynamic microphone, and removed the microphone part. This piece was too large to fit inside my telephone receiver, so I needed to use the Dremmel to cut it down to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Apologies for the lack of photos, I forgot to document this process)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soldered the new Microphone to the telephone receiver, and connected this to the Arduino enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_enclosure/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am considering wiring up the Arduino directly to the ‘bells’ instead of faking the ‘ring’ with speakers, however I’m not sure this is the best use of a half-day/days work. The case seems to create a nice amount of resonance, even without ‘speaker holes’.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my Physical Computing final, I needed to hack an old telephone that will be used to interact with a pile of electronic junk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Concept Development ‘Talking to Machines’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Concept Development 'Talking to Machines'" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html">&lt;p&gt;This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time sketching. And eventually I arrived at this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the impracticality, implausibility and difficulty of the ‘interactive room’ aspect of the project, I have scaled down the project and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it became clear that to power 5+ monitors on my laptop, I would need expensive adapters or a secondary computer or GPU. This started to sound like more hassle than it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, The room of monitors has been replaced with an obelisk of found-electronics. This may involve anything from televisions, microwaves, Furby’s and minibar fridges. All of these items will have projection screens retrofitted to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interaction has also been overhauled. Rather than using depth sensors and movement the main interaction now is done through the phone in a sedentary position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the participant sits down, a phone on their right will start ringing. They will answer the phone to find that their voice creates  a swelling feedback loop that influences and effects the images that they see in the frightening obelisk in front of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obelisk is a monsterous internet of things, and is still intended to be scary or unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that this new direction makes the act of ‘communicating with the machine’ more direct while there being much to explore in terms of fleshing out a satisfying voice-reactive experience through the telephone and video sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have begun  modifying the telephone so that it can react interactively, and interface with my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The microphone is being replaced with microphone that will provide a separate pre-amplified signal to my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also begun laser cutting scrap materials to start getting the ‘retrofit screens’ ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to wiring up the telephone, the ringer and the screens all together, and getting into fleshing out and designing the audio-visual interaction.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’. I spent a lot of time sketching. And eventually I arrived at this: Due to the impracticality, implausibility and difficulty of the ‘interactive room’ aspect of the project, I have scaled down the project and interaction. Furthermore, it became clear that to power 5+ monitors on my laptop, I would need expensive adapters or a secondary computer or GPU. This started to sound like more hassle than it was worth. As a result, The room of monitors has been replaced with an obelisk of found-electronics. This may involve anything from televisions, microwaves, Furby’s and minibar fridges. All of these items will have projection screens retrofitted to them. The interaction has also been overhauled. Rather than using depth sensors and movement the main interaction now is done through the phone in a sedentary position. When the participant sits down, a phone on their right will start ringing. They will answer the phone to find that their voice creates a swelling feedback loop that influences and effects the images that they see in the frightening obelisk in front of them. The obelisk is a monsterous internet of things, and is still intended to be scary or unsettling. I believe that this new direction makes the act of ‘communicating with the machine’ more direct while there being much to explore in terms of fleshing out a satisfying voice-reactive experience through the telephone and video sculpture. I have begun modifying the telephone so that it can react interactively, and interface with my audio interface. The microphone is being replaced with microphone that will provide a separate pre-amplified signal to my audio interface. I have also begun laser cutting scrap materials to start getting the ‘retrofit screens’ ready. CONCLUSION Looking forward to wiring up the telephone, the ringer and the screens all together, and getting into fleshing out and designing the audio-visual interaction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Laser Cutting Projection Feature</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laser Cutting Projection Feature" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50W Laser Cutter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8” Scrap wood&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measuring calliper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old Tv’s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an art installation I am building,  I am wanting to retrofit projection surfaces
onto an assortment of electronics and other junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in this process was to measure the orifices that the screens would be attached to with a calliper.
Then, the shape is drawn in illustrator and sent to the laser cutter for a first draft on disposable material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, a process of trial and error followed. The calliper was used to try and reduce the ‘gaps’.
As the margin of error became smaller, it became more and more difficult to close what is left of the ‘gaps’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For televisions that have an unusual shape, I used a levelling tool to take a photo of the camera from a birds eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this image into illustrator, reduced the opacity of the image and traced it to try and get a good approximation of the inner ellipse shape.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results, after much trial and error were pretty good. However, perhaps not good enough just yet to waste my acrylic on ;).
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to keep refining this technique, and will laser cut to acrylic when I have it very smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another possibility would be to abandon the laser cutter and paint projector paint over surfaces where this is possible (the glass of screens etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">PARTS AND TOOLS 50W Laser Cutter 1/8” Scrap wood Adobe Illustrator Measuring calliper Old Tv’s For an art installation I am building, I am wanting to retrofit projection surfaces onto an assortment of electronics and other junk. The first step in this process was to measure the orifices that the screens would be attached to with a calliper. Then, the shape is drawn in illustrator and sent to the laser cutter for a first draft on disposable material. After this, a process of trial and error followed. The calliper was used to try and reduce the ‘gaps’. As the margin of error became smaller, it became more and more difficult to close what is left of the ‘gaps’. For televisions that have an unusual shape, I used a levelling tool to take a photo of the camera from a birds eye. I took this image into illustrator, reduced the opacity of the image and traced it to try and get a good approximation of the inner ellipse shape. The results, after much trial and error were pretty good. However, perhaps not good enough just yet to waste my acrylic on ;). CONCLUSION I plan to keep refining this technique, and will laser cut to acrylic when I have it very smooth. Another possibility would be to abandon the laser cutter and paint projector paint over surfaces where this is possible (the glass of screens etc.).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Interference play feedback</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Interference play feedback" /><published>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback.html">&lt;p&gt;After demonstrating a basic ‘play’ version of my proposed visual sculpture, I received some helpful feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a clip of the prototype being demonstrated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241957118&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will attempt to summarise my impression of the feedback here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the transition from ‘no interference’ to ‘full interference’ is not dramatic enough. The screens move from one type of disorientation to another and as a result the sense of contrast is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution to this would be to play with ‘off states’ and static images. Several of the monitors might be off unless somebody is nearby. When they turn on they might ‘grab’ an image and come to life gradually as the user approaches. I plan to start playing with tensions between the projected and the static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody mentioned that the project seemed like it was attempting to reveal to the participant their greatest fears. This reminded me of Andrei Tarkovsky’s film &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stalker_(1979_film)&quot;&gt;Stalker&lt;/a&gt; which depicted a place called ‘the Zone’ where ‘tourists’ could be smuggled inside to experience a mysterious ‘other’ intelligence. It was ambiguous what the nature of the communication was, but the experience of this ‘Zone’ seemed to cause an existential fissure for these morbidly curious tourists. This is worth keeping in mind for further concept development and I consider this to be another way of exploring a related idea. Sounds like it is time to finally read the original novel on which the film is based  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roadside_Picnic&quot;&gt;Roadside Picnic&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common criticism was that the interactivity needs to be developed to make the concept of ‘communicating with the machine’ clearer and more purposeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One potential solution to this would be to incorporate a Kinect sensor and incorporate user movement data into the projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a positive feedback with respect to the custom fabricated projection screens. However, the front projection technique restricts straight-forward interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be embraced as a constraint with the aid of a light sensor. A computer could be set up to be notified when the projection is interrupted. This could trigger another interaction or be countered by a rear projection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions of rear or front projection aside, I plan to continue prototyping projection surfaces and screen options that could be used for the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others mentioned that it would be nice to be able to ‘touch’ the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Sherwood and Mike Allison’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://aaron-sherwood.com/works/firewall/&quot;&gt;Firewall&lt;/a&gt;  is a worthy reference for its use of stretched spandex sheets and rear projection mapping to create an interactive surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/54882144&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of interaction could be a great fit for my project, however I imagine that it might be difficult to cleanly communicate to the users that they can ‘touch’ the monitors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After demonstrating a basic ‘play’ version of my proposed visual sculpture, I received some helpful feedback.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Modular projection mapping surface (Part 1)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modular projection mapping surface (Part 1)" /><published>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1.html">&lt;p&gt;I built some surfaces that could be projected on and used for prototyping installations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Coroplast sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drills and drill bits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanding Paper or Sanding Machine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Gun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban Saw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stanley Knife aka. Exacto Blade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gridded cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the materials, I had to spend time measuring and drawing lines in the Coroplast to start cutting up the faces that would be used to assemble the surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was challenging, due to the size of the Coroplast sheets that I purchased and the limited space I had access to in ITP’s fabrication shop. I found that my results were improved as soon as I started orienting the ruler and the tape measure with the assistance of a gridded cutting board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another challenge is accounting for the various ways that the box overlaps and underlapping at its edges. I settled on the following dimensions by taking into account the thickness of the material (0.157”):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6”x6” (Left and Right)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7”x6” (Front and Back)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7.314”x6” (Top and Bottom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the lines had been drawn, I started cutting up the board with the blade. Better results were achieved when cuts were proceeded by a single, light handed incision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw together a little ‘pancake’ with Hot Glue to get a sense of how my calculations were stacking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to cut up some wood cubes to give the structure better support at its corners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the Ban Saw to cut up a piece of scrap wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vice came in handy to work with some of the irregular combinations of pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pieces were assembled together with hot glue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pieces were arranged and tested with Touch designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Coroplast is cheap and works well with projectors; introducing it into a Fabrication process introduces some constraints. The flexibility (amount of ‘give’) of the material makes it difficult to work with saws. The flammability prevents use with lazer cutters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stanley Knife (Exacto!) requires some skill and getting used to, but once practiced provides a great deal of control and precision. With further practice, more advanced surfaces for projection mapping could be designed and implemented with such techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next blog post will detail experimenting  with magnets to make these surfaces both modular and compose-able.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I built some surfaces that could be projected on and used for prototyping installations. PARTS AND TOOLS White Coroplast sheets Drills and drill bits Sanding Paper or Sanding Machine Glue Gun Ban Saw Stanley Knife aka. Exacto Blade Gridded cutting board Once I had the materials, I had to spend time measuring and drawing lines in the Coroplast to start cutting up the faces that would be used to assemble the surfaces. This was challenging, due to the size of the Coroplast sheets that I purchased and the limited space I had access to in ITP’s fabrication shop. I found that my results were improved as soon as I started orienting the ruler and the tape measure with the assistance of a gridded cutting board. Another challenge is accounting for the various ways that the box overlaps and underlapping at its edges. I settled on the following dimensions by taking into account the thickness of the material (0.157”): 6”x6” (Left and Right) 7”x6” (Front and Back) 7.314”x6” (Top and Bottom) Once the lines had been drawn, I started cutting up the board with the blade. Better results were achieved when cuts were proceeded by a single, light handed incision. I threw together a little ‘pancake’ with Hot Glue to get a sense of how my calculations were stacking up. I decided to cut up some wood cubes to give the structure better support at its corners. I used the Ban Saw to cut up a piece of scrap wood. A vice came in handy to work with some of the irregular combinations of pieces. The pieces were assembled together with hot glue. The pieces were arranged and tested with Touch designer. CONCLUSION While Coroplast is cheap and works well with projectors; introducing it into a Fabrication process introduces some constraints. The flexibility (amount of ‘give’) of the material makes it difficult to work with saws. The flammability prevents use with lazer cutters. The Stanley Knife (Exacto!) requires some skill and getting used to, but once practiced provides a great deal of control and precision. With further practice, more advanced surfaces for projection mapping could be designed and implemented with such techniques. The next blog post will detail experimenting with magnets to make these surfaces both modular and compose-able.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Interference play demonstration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Interference play demonstration" /><published>2017-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration.html">&lt;p&gt;Human Interference is an interactive video sculpture in progress. The piece looks to explore the experience of making contact with another intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for this piece struck me when browsing artist and educator &lt;a href=&quot;http://moodvector.com&quot;&gt;Gregory Shakar’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://moodvector.com/acfc/acfc_installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate reaction to this image was that the computers were looking in my direction - curious about me. Despite the colours, and the playful interface I sense something sinister lurking under the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will attempt to draw participants into this sinister space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to make ‘contact’ with a machine? Consumer electronics and AI assistants present us with a friendly, anthropomorphized face who help optimize and enhance our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project speculates on a future where contact is made with another intelligence, however the communication has been abstracted. Human language is futile in traversing this void between man and machine.  However, our presence and proximity to the network disrupts it’s usual operation. It is through our ability to disrupt the machine that we are able to learn something of its true nature. This form of ‘communication’ produces a fissure in our sense of a stable, human-definable reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content will be displayed on old computer monitors and driven by Touch Designer and Max MSP. Depth sensors determine whether the participant is inside or outside the machine space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interaction, in more literal terms, will involve the participant catching a glimpse from afar.  It will appear simple, and alluring. As the participant approaches the space, they will get a sense of their proximity causing disruptions. Feedback loops will be triggered to enhance the sense of disorientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they enter the space, we see a destruction of familiar forms, and a bombardment of industrial, cold, electrical sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN CONSIDERATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other lazer switches may be set up to trigger lighting, sound and video effects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kinect data to increase interactivity with screen display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POSSIBILITIES FOR LURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ambient music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple, bold colours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some white boarding to try and clarify some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first idea was deep-diving into the science-fiction context to this installation. &lt;a href=&quot;ccru.net/swarm1/1_melt.htm&quot;&gt;Nick Land’s Meltdown&lt;/a&gt; short piece of speculative, science fiction was an inspiration. Each monitor contains a different fragment of the context of imagined world. We have human slaves, a human vision config, automated trading platforms, ‘neural interfaces’ and empty e-sports arenas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An imagined science-fiction universe remains important for my idea generation process, however I found this literal representation to be lacking in subtlety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/human_interference_process/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more minimal options including computer communication through voice chat and LED’s to signify machine to machine communication .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/human_interference_process/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started experimenting with Touch Designer and GLSL shaders to explore feedback effects. The feedback expresses a recursive void which I felt fit in naturally with my concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241825810&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241825832&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased with these results, however it needs to be taken further. To make this scarier, audio is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built some projection mapping surfaces to allow for some more high fidelity prototyping of the aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping illustrated the need for more varied content, effects and interactive development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Human Interference is an interactive video sculpture in progress. The piece looks to explore the experience of making contact with another intelligence.</summary></entry></feed>