<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-15T03:35:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sam Hains</title><subtitle>Sam Hains is a programmer and designer from Melbourne, Australia. He is currently completing his Masters degree at NYU's ITP program.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Concept Development ‘Talking to Machines’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Concept Development 'Talking to Machines'" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/15/concept-development-talking-to-machines.html">&lt;p&gt;This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time sketching. And eventually I arrived at this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the impracticality, implausibility and difficulty of the ‘interactive room’ aspect of the project, I have scaled down the project and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it became clear that to power 5+ monitors on my laptop, I would need expensive adapters or a secondary computer or GPU. This started to sound like more hassle than it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, The room of monitors has been replaced with an obelisk of found-electronics. This may involve anything from televisions, microwaves, Furby’s and minibar fridges. All of these items will have projection screens retrofitted to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interaction has also been overhauled. Rather than using depth sensors and movement the main interaction now is done through the phone in a sedentary position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the participant sits down, a phone on their right will start ringing. They will answer the phone to find that their voice creates  a swelling feedback loop that influences and effects the images that they see in the frightening obelisk in front of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obelisk is a monsterous internet of things, and is still intended to be scary or unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that this new direction makes the act of ‘communicating with the machine’ more direct while there being much to explore in terms of fleshing out a satisfying voice-reactive experience through the telephone and video sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have begun  modifying the telephone so that it can react interactively, and interface with my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The microphone is being replaced with microphone that will provide a separate pre-amplified signal to my audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also begun laser cutting scrap materials to start getting the ‘retrofit screens’ ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pcomm_final_concept_dev/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to wiring up the telephone, the ringer and the screens all together, and getting into fleshing out and designing the audio-visual interaction.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week was spent iterating on design ideas, and developing and refining my concept for final. The project has been renamed ‘Taking to machines’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Laser Cutting Projection Feature</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laser Cutting Projection Feature" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/15/laser-cutting-projection-features.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50W Laser Cutter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8” Scrap wood&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measuring calliper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old Tv’s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an art installation I am building,  I am wanting to retrofit projection surfaces
onto an assortment of electronics and other junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in this process was to measure the orifices that the screens would be attached to with a calliper.
Then, the shape is drawn in illustrator and sent to the laser cutter for a first draft on disposable material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, a process of trial and error followed. The calliper was used to try and reduce the ‘gaps’.
As the margin of error became smaller, it became more and more difficult to close what is left of the ‘gaps’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For televisions that have an unusual shape, I used a levelling tool to take a photo of the camera from a birds eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this image into illustrator, reduced the opacity of the image and traced it to try and get a good approximation of the inner ellipse shape.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results, after much trial and error were pretty good. However, perhaps not good enough just yet to waste my acrylic on ;).
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/fab_laser_cutter/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to keep refining this technique, and will laser cut to acrylic when I have it very smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another possibility would be to abandon the laser cutter and paint projector paint over surfaces where this is possible (the glass of screens etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">PARTS AND TOOLS</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Interference play feedback</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Interference play feedback" /><published>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/08/human-interference-feedback.html">&lt;p&gt;After demonstrating a basic ‘play’ version of my proposed visual sculpture, I received some helpful feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a clip of the prototype being demonstrated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241957118&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will attempt to summarise my impression of the feedback here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the transition from ‘no interference’ to ‘full interference’ is not dramatic enough. The screens move from one type of disorientation to another and as a result the sense of contrast is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution to this would be to play with ‘off states’ and static images. Several of the monitors might be off unless somebody is nearby. When they turn on they might ‘grab’ an image and come to life gradually as the user approaches. I plan to start playing with tensions between the projected and the static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody mentioned that the project seemed like it was attempting to reveal to the participant their greatest fears. This reminded me of Andrei Tarkovsky’s film &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stalker_(1979_film)&quot;&gt;Stalker&lt;/a&gt; which depicted a place called ‘the Zone’ where ‘tourists’ could be smuggled inside to experience a mysterious ‘other’ intelligence. It was ambiguous what the nature of the communication was, but the experience of this ‘Zone’ seemed to cause an existential fissure for these morbidly curious tourists. This is worth keeping in mind for further concept development and I consider this to be another way of exploring a related idea. Sounds like it is time to finally read the original novel on which the film is based  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roadside_Picnic&quot;&gt;Roadside Picnic&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common criticism was that the interactivity needs to be developed to make the concept of ‘communicating with the machine’ clearer and more purposeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One potential solution to this would be to incorporate a Kinect sensor and incorporate user movement data into the projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a positive feedback with respect to the custom fabricated projection screens. However, the front projection technique restricts straight-forward interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be embraced as a constraint with the aid of a light sensor. A computer could be set up to be notified when the projection is interrupted. This could trigger another interaction or be countered by a rear projection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions of rear or front projection aside, I plan to continue prototyping projection surfaces and screen options that could be used for the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others mentioned that it would be nice to be able to ‘touch’ the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Sherwood and Mike Allison’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://aaron-sherwood.com/works/firewall/&quot;&gt;Firewall&lt;/a&gt;  is a worthy reference for its use of stretched spandex sheets and rear projection mapping to create an interactive surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/54882144&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of interaction could be a great fit for my project, however I imagine that it might be difficult to cleanly communicate to the users that they can ‘touch’ the monitors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After demonstrating a basic ‘play’ version of my proposed visual sculpture, I received some helpful feedback.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Modular projection mapping surface (Part 1)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modular projection mapping surface (Part 1)" /><published>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/11/08/modular-projection-mapping-surface-p-1.html">&lt;p&gt;I built some surfaces that could be projected on and used for prototyping installations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Coroplast sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drills and drill bits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanding Paper or Sanding Machine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Gun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban Saw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stanley Knife aka. Exacto Blade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gridded cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the materials, I had to spend time measuring and drawing lines in the Coroplast to start cutting up the faces that would be used to assemble the surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was challenging, due to the size of the Coroplast sheets that I purchased and the limited space I had access to in ITP’s fabrication shop. I found that my results were improved as soon as I started orienting the ruler and the tape measure with the assistance of a gridded cutting board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another challenge is accounting for the various ways that the box overlaps and underlapping at its edges. I settled on the following dimensions by taking into account the thickness of the material (0.157”):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6”x6” (Left and Right)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7”x6” (Front and Back)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7.314”x6” (Top and Bottom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the lines had been drawn, I started cutting up the board with the blade. Better results were achieved when cuts were proceeded by a single, light handed incision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw together a little ‘pancake’ with Hot Glue to get a sense of how my calculations were stacking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to cut up some wood cubes to give the structure better support at its corners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the Ban Saw to cut up a piece of scrap wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vice came in handy to work with some of the irregular combinations of pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pieces were assembled together with hot glue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pieces were arranged and tested with Touch designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Coroplast is cheap and works well with projectors; introducing it into a Fabrication process introduces some constraints. The flexibility (amount of ‘give’) of the material makes it difficult to work with saws. The flammability prevents use with lazer cutters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stanley Knife (Exacto!) requires some skill and getting used to, but once practiced provides a great deal of control and precision. With further practice, more advanced surfaces for projection mapping could be designed and implemented with such techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next blog post will detail experimenting  with magnets to make these surfaces both modular and compose-able.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I built some surfaces that could be projected on and used for prototyping installations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Interference play demonstration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Interference play demonstration" /><published>2017-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/physcomp/2017/11/07/human-interference-play-demonstration.html">&lt;p&gt;Human Interference is an interactive video sculpture in progress. The piece looks to explore the experience of making contact with another intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for this piece struck me when browsing artist and educator &lt;a href=&quot;http://moodvector.com&quot;&gt;Gregory Shakar’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://moodvector.com/acfc/acfc_installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate reaction to this image was that the computers were looking in my direction - curious about me. Despite the colours, and the playful interface I sense something sinister lurking under the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will attempt to draw participants into this sinister space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to make ‘contact’ with a machine? Consumer electronics and AI assistants present us with a friendly, anthropomorphized face who help optimize and enhance our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project speculates on a future where contact is made with another intelligence, however the communication has been abstracted. Human language is futile in traversing this void between man and machine.  However, our presence and proximity to the network disrupts it’s usual operation. It is through our ability to disrupt the machine that we are able to learn something of its true nature. This form of ‘communication’ produces a fissure in our sense of a stable, human-definable reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content will be displayed on old computer monitors and driven by Touch Designer and Max MSP. Depth sensors determine whether the participant is inside or outside the machine space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interaction, in more literal terms, will involve the participant catching a glimpse from afar.  It will appear simple, and alluring. As the participant approaches the space, they will get a sense of their proximity causing disruptions. Feedback loops will be triggered to enhance the sense of disorientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they enter the space, we see a destruction of familiar forms, and a bombardment of industrial, cold, electrical sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN CONSIDERATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other lazer switches may be set up to trigger lighting, sound and video effects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kinect data to increase interactivity with screen display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POSSIBILITIES FOR LURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ambient music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple, bold colours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some white boarding to try and clarify some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first idea was deep-diving into the science-fiction context to this installation. &lt;a href=&quot;ccru.net/swarm1/1_melt.htm&quot;&gt;Nick Land’s Meltdown&lt;/a&gt; short piece of speculative, science fiction was an inspiration. Each monitor contains a different fragment of the context of imagined world. We have human slaves, a human vision config, automated trading platforms, ‘neural interfaces’ and empty e-sports arenas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An imagined science-fiction universe remains important for my idea generation process, however I found this literal representation to be lacking in subtlety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/human_interference_process/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more minimal options including computer communication through voice chat and LED’s to signify machine to machine communication .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/human_interference_process/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started experimenting with Touch Designer and GLSL shaders to explore feedback effects. The feedback expresses a recursive void which I felt fit in naturally with my concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241825810&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/241825832&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased with these results, however it needs to be taken further. To make this scarier, audio is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built some projection mapping surfaces to allow for some more high fidelity prototyping of the aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/modular_projector/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping illustrated the need for more varied content, effects and interactive development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Human Interference is an interactive video sculpture in progress. The piece looks to explore the experience of making contact with another intelligence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making an Altoid can into a laser</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/10/31/making-a-light.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making an Altoid can into a laser" /><published>2017-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/10/31/making-a-light</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/intro-fab/2017/10/31/making-a-light.html">&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months of eager  overcomplicating,  I decided I would approach the first Fabrication assignment as simply, and as cheaply as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PARTS AND TOOLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Altoid Tin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red and black wires&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3V red laser diode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic switch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soldering Iron with wire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helping hands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drills and drill bits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanding Paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glue Gun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with an Altoid tin, I pulled out  a range  of drills so that I could slowly and progressively drill holes in the Altoid can for the laser and switch to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/introfab_1_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to drill the hole. This proved to be a little more complicated to do ‘perfectly’ than imagined. The drill created a lot of ‘blowout’  with the metal, which was difficult to sand without wrecking the finish on the interior of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/introfab_1_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to solder the wires to the switches and the laser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/intro_fab_1_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a glue gun to add some protection to the wires that had been exposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/intro_fab_1_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I connected all the wires to power to test that everything was working correctly. After confirming this, the next step was to use the glue gun to attach the laser diode to the hole that was drilled and to screw in the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/intro_fab_1_7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And there it is, a very simple laser in an Altoid tin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/intro_fab_1_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laser diode I bought from Tinkersphere, and was not very high quality. The overall light emitted from the laser is a little lacklustre. A quality laser diode may improve my beam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to spend some time looking into techniques to drill into tin in a neater way if I was to do this again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After a couple of months of eager overcomplicating, I decided I would approach the first Fabrication assignment as simply, and as cheaply as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PLUTO (C:)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/faking-the-news/2017/10/19/pluto-community-networking-evolved.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLUTO (C:)" /><published>2017-10-19T17:12:02-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T17:12:02-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/faking-the-news/2017/10/19/pluto-community-networking-evolved</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/faking-the-news/2017/10/19/pluto-community-networking-evolved.html">&lt;p&gt;For my final project for ‘Faking the news’, I build a web community that has been overun by a swarm of bots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;pluto-c.net&quot;&gt;http://pluto-c.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/pluto-1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a combination of real-time scraping of data from &lt;a href=&quot;ilxor.com&quot;&gt;ilxor&lt;/a&gt;, subreddits&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; /r/politics&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/The_Donald/&quot;&gt; /r/The_Donald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/genekogan/ebd77196e4bf0705db51f86431099e57&quot;&gt;google image search scraping&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpedm20/DCGAN-tensorflow&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/models/tree/master/im2txt&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;- the Pluto-C program creates a family of deranged bots reflecting forum and internet culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;pluto-c.net/forum/4-memiverse&quot;&gt;memiverse sub-forum&lt;/a&gt; - I am particularly happy with. The aesthetics of online meme discussions lead themselves to particularly disturbing robot reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/meme-dcgan-1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the forum was an attempt to create the ‘feeling’ of an abandoned web space. It was designed to be both anachronistic but also a love letter to the aesthetics of the nascent web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the machines have moved in, we experience a sense of ‘digital gentrification’ as the once familiar interface of the message board has becomes alien to us. We are no longer relevant or necessary. I like to think of the analogy of an abandoned theme park that is now home to a swarm of insects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is a metaphor for the current state of the internet in 2017 and I hope that the basic sense of the internet as a ‘human space’  is perverted by the experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my final project for ‘Faking the news’, I build a web community that has been overun by a swarm of bots.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apocalyptic Business Cards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/19/apocalyptic-business-cards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apocalyptic Business Cards" /><published>2017-10-19T16:51:31-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T16:51:31-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/19/apocalyptic-business-cards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/19/apocalyptic-business-cards.html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to approach the task of Business card in a more formal fashion than some of my previous graphic design experiments. I started my explorations by studying the techniques and design strategies of dutch design agency, &lt;a href=&quot;http://metahaven.net/&quot;&gt;Metahaven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest to me was their series of posters for the Holland festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/5403f19912bfeed40506693eddd1b882.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/dc519c847f44faa3db7a36ee210362b7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was captivated by the use of overlapping image outlines, which are filled in to create unusual and messy forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling self-conscious about the idea handing someone a business card, I thought it would be funny to highlight the absurdity of this gesture by etching my name in an image of a burning planet earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/final_card.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/final_red.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel these are the most successful designs so far in my Graphic Design journey, and they are a testiment to a process that focuses more on studying the masters and learning from existing design patterns. This makes sense given how new I am to this form of communication.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I decided to approach the task of Business card in a more formal fashion than some of my previous graphic design experiments. I started my explorations by studying the techniques and design strategies of dutch design agency, Metahaven.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ITP Winter Poster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/vislang/2017/10/12/itp-winter-poster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ITP Winter Poster" /><published>2017-10-12T13:50:14-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-12T13:50:14-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/vislang/2017/10/12/itp-winter-poster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/vislang/2017/10/12/itp-winter-poster.html">&lt;p&gt;For my submission to the ITP Winter Show Poster, I decided I would create a composition based on 3D scans of ITP students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Skanect with a Structure Sensor to do the scans.  I then imported the scans into Cinema4d where I experimented with various compositions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main design problem that I faced was wanting to express the artificiality of the 3D scans in a 2D space. I wanted to distance myself from perfection, but also make it clear that these were not simply doctored photographs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experimented with cell shading to emphasise the 3D nature of the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/reduced_black_outlines.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleased with these results, and I attempted to composit these back onto the models in photoshop.  Unfortunately,  I felt this made the design too ‘busy’ and ‘gadgety’. The focus was distracted to be on the models and their inherent aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/cells.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are devices that strive towards perfection, and fall short. I believe there is a poetry in the failure of these ambitious devices, and in the vulnerability that they communicate in their nascent development phase. I like the artifacts that the technology creates, so I decided to emphasise the decay and imperfections and ended with this design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/poster-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-friends-are-lukewarm-about-me&quot;&gt;My Friends Are Lukewarm About Me&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/237981904&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my submission to the ITP Winter Show Poster, I decided I would create a composition based on 3D scans of ITP students.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Default Colours and Speculative Interface</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/03/default-colours-speculative-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Default Colours and Speculative Interface" /><published>2017-10-03T07:16:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-03T07:16:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/03/default-colours-speculative-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/vlang/2017/10/03/default-colours-speculative-design.html">&lt;p&gt;For Visual Language class, at ITP, we were given the task of designing 6 graphics, based on a colour palette that reflected ones personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first attempted to do this assignment in Cinema4D, as I want to learn how to design in 3D programs. However, I underestimated how challenging this would be technically and creatively, and ended up moving back to illustrator due to time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/flower_sculpture2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In illustrator my attempts continued to follow the process of playing with colour and form in an improvised way. The results were not good. My attempts to define myself with a colour scheme also felt superficial and abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that in order to connect with the task, I needed to come up with a concept that would drive the design.  I began my explorations by examining the aesthetics and design of anachronistic web interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are abstractions of the web forums ‘hipinion’ and ‘ilxor’ respectively. The text has been removed to express the aesthetic backdrop of these virtual spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/hipinion.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/ilxor.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attempted to create collages from these forum interfaces. Unsatisfied with the results, I started to experiment with Netscape and windows 95 interface components.  For this process I was inspired by Jan Robert Leegte’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhizome.org/art/artbase/artwork/untitledscrollbars/&quot;&gt;scrollbars&lt;/a&gt;, where the artist took  elements from the OSX interface and made collages with the scrollbars and other existing elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in ‘default’ colours. The designer traditionally transforms defaults into design, however it is an interesting constraint to me when design is forced to be made with defaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colour palette selected is monochromatic, with the exception of ‘Pure Blue’, which I find striking in contrast to monochromatic grey. It has a soothing quality, but there is also something unnatural and surreal about its purity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While experimenting with these components, the idea evolved into creating a speculative interface.  The interface has not been designed for the human ‘User’ as we understand it. The graphical interface would suggest it is not an interface optimized for a machine either.  A human that encounters such an interface might need to decode it or use a scanning interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/palette_w4-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For Visual Language class, at ITP, we were given the task of designing 6 graphics, based on a colour palette that reflected ones personality.</summary></entry></feed>